Guide to the Clark P. Read academic papers, 1952-1971 UA 327
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Clark P. Read academic papers
1952-1971
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Read, Clark P.
UA 327
1 Linear Feet (1 box)
Academic papers of Dr. Clark P. Read. Includes correspondence, collected publications, and personal research completed between the years 1952 and 1971.
Biographical / Historical
Clark P. Read was born February 4, 1921 in Fort Worth Texas. He recieved his B.A., M.A. and Ph.D. from Rice University and served as Assistant Professor of Zoology from University of California Los Angeles and Associate Professor of Parasitology at John Hopkins University before returning to serve as Professor of Biology at Rice in 1959. Dr. Read served as Chair of the Biology Department at Rice from 1964 to 1969 and 1972 to 1974. In 1966 Read served on the Board of Trustees of the Marine Biological Laboratory in Woods Hole, MA. He also was a epidemiology professor at the Baylor School of Medicine from 1961 to 1965. He was renown for his research in parasitology, which can be seen in his research notes and correspondence during his time at UCLA. Dr. Read died when he was 52 years old on December 23, 1973.
Scope and Contents
Clark P. Read's academic papers include an extensive amount of correspondence, organized by name of recipient and sender,during his time at UCLA and Johns Hopkins University, 1954 to 1959. The collection also includes his personal research notes and lab data between the years 1952 and 1971. Topics covered in his research notes include, but are not limited to, his work in parasitology and worms. The collection also includes some of Read's collected publications.
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
Transferred to the Woodson Research Center 2013.
Index Terms
Subjects
Education; Biology; Universities and colleges
Document Types
reports; notes; letters (correspondence)
- Series I. Correspondence, 1954-1959, 165967
  - Correspondence A, 1954-1959; 165971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence B, 1955-1959; 165972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence C, 1954-1959; 165973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence D-F, 1954-1959; 165974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence G, 1954-1959; 165975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence H-J, 1954-1959; 165976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence K-L, 1954-1959; 165977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence M, 1954-1959; 165978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II. Research Notes, 1952-1971, 165996
  - Research Notes, 01/1952; 165981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Research Notes, 1956-1957; 165982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Research Notes, Spring 1957; 165983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Research Notes (1 of 2), Summer 1957; 165984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Research Notes (2 of 2), Summer 1957; 165985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Research Notes, 1958; 165986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Research Notes, Summer 1958; 165987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Research Notes, 1959; 165988 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Research Notes, 1960; 165989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Research Notes (1 of 2), 1961-1962; 165990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Research Notes (2 of 2), 1961-1962; 165991 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Research Notes, Fall 1962; 165992 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Research Notes, 1969; 165993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Research Notes, 1971; 165994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Series III. Printed Materials, 1861-1966, 165997
  - Beshreibung Zweier Neuertaenioden Aus Dem Menschen, 1861; 165970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bilhaziasis Survey in Eritrea, Ethiopia, the British and Italian Somalilands, The Sudan and the Yemen, 1953; 165969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Coastal and Estuarine Waters in the United States, 1967; 165968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Instructor's Manual for Bio 380, n.d.; 165979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Research and Research Training on the Biology of the Whole Organism, 1966; 165980 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Translation of "Studies on the Constitution and Protein Metabolism of Ascaris Lumbriroides", 1955; 165995 (Box 1, Folder 28)